Finding Aid for Freemasons. Golden Rule Lodge No. 159 (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records, 1864-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Freemasons, Golden Rule Lodge No. 159 (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records 1864-1997
Freemasons. Golden Rule Lodge No. 159 (Ann Arbor, Mich.).
2 linear feet and 18 oversize volumes
2010012 Bd 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records came from the Lodge (donor no. 10272 ) in 2009.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Freemason Golden Rule Lodge No. 159 was formed in Ann Arbor, Michigan in 1865. In 1927, the lodge had 1036 members. From this high mark, membership would decline to 516 in 1979. In the 1990s, among the charitable organizations supported by the Lodge was the Juvenile Diabetes Foundation. The Lodge also provided scholarships for area high school students.
The records of the Golden Rule Lodge No. 159, Ann Arbor, Michigan include minutes of the special and regular meetings of the lodge, membership materials, by-laws, and some financial records. Included is a volume of memorial programs for past state grand masters.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Freemasons. Golden Rule Lodge No. 159 (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Freemasons--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- Minutes of Special and Regular Communications (meetings)
  - 1864-1872 (Volume 1)
  - 1873-1885 (Volume 2)
  - 1886-1894 (Volume 3)
  - 1894-1901 (Volume 4)
  - 1901-1907 (Volume 5)
  - 1907-1913 (Volume 6)
  - 1913-1917 (Volume 7)
  - 1917-1919 (Volume 8)
  - 1919-1921 (Volume 9)
  - 1922-1926 (Volume 10)
  - 1927-1931 (Volume 11)
  - 1932-1942 (Volume 12)
  - 1943-1949 (Volume 13)
  - 1950-1956 (Volume 14)
  - 1957-1959 (Volume 15)
  - [volumes for 1960-1970 not received]
  - 1971-1979 (Volume 16)
  - 1980-1992 (Volume 17)
  - 1993-1997 (Box 1)
- Other records
  - By-laws (Box 1)
  - Registers of Officers, Members and Visitors
    - 1905-1906 (Box 1)
      (combined volume for Golden Rule Lodge 159 and Fraternity Lodge 262)
    - 1985-1995 (Box 1)
  - Souvenir programs, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Informational material; include lists, history, etc. (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous records, 1994-1997 (Box 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Reports of Secretary-Treasurer and Finance Committee, 1860s-1898 (scattered dates) (Box 1)
      (also include some sundry reports)
    - Miscellaneous vouchers, bills, receipts (Box 1)
  - Record of Memorials (past grand masters) (Volume 18)
- Membership materials
  - Annual Return to the Grand Lodge F. & A. M., 1865-1922, 1 folder and 1 expandable folder (Box 2)
    (include lists of officers, members, transfers, rejected applicants, etc.)
  - Questionnaires submitted by applicants for membership, 1920s (Box 2)
  - Petitions, applications, summons, 3 expandable folders (Box 2)
  - Charges against members (mainly for non-payment of dues) (Box 2)
  - Black Book (expulsion of members mainly for non-payment of dues), 1874-1895 (Box 2)
    (include rejected, suspended and expelled in sister lodges, 1890-1898)
  - Membership miscellaneous (Box 2)